hassle.com 2019-10-13

# Helpling

We are Teddle Limited. We own and operate www.helpling.co.uk (the site) and we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We are a limited company registered in England and Wales under company number 07991751 and have our registered office at Unit CRLG/G, Cranmer House, 39 Brixton Road, London, SW9 6DZ, UK. Our main trading address is Unit CRLG/G, Cranmer House, 39 Brixton Road, London, SW9 6DZ, UK and our VAT number is GB 132 8488 02.

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act) and the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the data controller is Teddle Limited, hereinafter referred to as “HELPLING”, and we are registered on the Information Commissioner’s Register of Data Controllers under registration number Z3229504.

The use of this website may involve the processing of personal information. The intention of this privacy policy is to provide you with an overview of these processes so that you can understand them. In order to ensure fair processing, we would also like to inform you about your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act) and the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

1\. General information

a. Contact

If you have any questions or suggestions about this information or would like to contact us to exercise your rights, please contact us at: Teddle Limited, Unit CRLG/G, Cranmer House, 39 Brixton Road, London, SW9 6DZ; E-Mail: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

b. General information on the processing of personal data

The use of this website may result in the processing of personal data. The term “personal data” under data protection law refers to all information relating to a specific or identifiable person. An IP address can also be considered personal data. An IP address is assigned to each device connected to the internet by the internet service provider, so that it can send and receive data. When you use the website, we collect data that you provide yourself. In addition, when you use the website, we automatically collect certain information about your use of it.

We process personal data in compliance with the relevant data protection regulations of the GDPR and the Act. We will only process data where we are legally permitted to do so. When you use this website, we will process personal data only with your consent (Article 6, paragraph 1, (a), GDPR), for the performance of a contract to which you are a party, or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract (Article 6, paragraph 1, (b), GDPR), for compliance with a legal obligation (Article 6, paragraph 1, (c), GDPR), or if the processing is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party, except where such interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms which require the protection of personal data (Article 6, paragraph 1, (f), GDPR), If you are applying for an open position with us we will additionally process your personal data in connection with your interest in future employment with us (Article 26, paragraph 1, GDPR).

c. Duration of Storage

Unless otherwise stated in the following sections, we will store the data only as long as necessary to achieve the purpose of processing, or to fulfil our contractual or statutory obligations. Such statutory storage duties may result especially from commercial or tax law regulations.

d. Technical Service Providers

If not specified otherwise in the following notes the processing of data is done on servers of technical service providers, which were contracted by us to do so. These service providers process data strictly by our instructions and are contractually committed to ensure adequate technical and organizational data protection measures.

2\. Special notes for users

In the following we will describe how we process data when you book household services via our platform and request the service of a cleaner.

a. Booking of household services

To book household services via our website you are required to register with us and create your own Helpling account. This profile is necessary to identify potential service providers that offer their services in the area requested and based on additional criteria you put forward.

We collect the following information:

First name, last name, email address, telephone number, street, house number, additional address information, postcode, city, preferred method of payment (hereinafter combined referred to as “user profile data”); type of service requested and additional services as well as the date, time and duration of the requested service; information if service is one-off or recurring (hereinafter combined referred to as “booking data”; time of user profile creation and update;

In addition, you are able to specify the following information on a voluntary basis:

Presence of domestic animals, disposal site for waste, availability of parking spots, specification of special needs (e.g. certain priorities or rooms, which should not be included in the service requested), possible requirements regarding cleaning materials, information on how the service provider can access your apartment (e.g. keys are with neighbour or you are at home).

HELPLING transfers the user profile data, booking data and possible additional information provided by you on a voluntary basis for the purpose of arranging household services to service providers you selected during the booking process plus potentially other service providers that fit your booking criteria.

If a booking request is accepted and a contract between you and a cleaner is confirmed HELPLING also processes your user profile data for the purpose of booking support, fulfilment, completion, accounting and follow-up assistance of the respective booked cleans and services as well as contracts including additional related actions such as invoices, credit, claims, cancellations etc.

On top of that we use user profile data, especially your telephone number, to send out automated messages to notify and remind you of upcoming cleaning events and services.

HELPLING also uses the booking data to the required extent to generate invoices for the delivered services of the partner and any following necessary assistance (e.g. in case of inadequate service delivery of cleaner).

In addition we transfer, depending on the chosen method of payment, your credit card data (card number, expiry date, security code) or your bank account details (hereinafter also referred to as “payment data”), that HELPLING collects in connection to the booking, to the licensed payment provider Stripe Payments Europe Limited, The One Building, 1 Grand Canal Street Lower, Dublin 2, Ireland , cooperating with us for the purpose of handling of payments (hereinafter referred to as “payment provider”). The payment provider is collecting, processing and using the payment data for the purpose of handling of payments respectively collecting the receivables from your bank account. There is no additional storage of your payment data.

As part of our fulfilment, we store the services you booked and that were delivered by a cleaner including created invoices in your user profile, so that we are able to provide access to this information at a later point in time.

The legal basis for the described data processing is Article 6, paragraph 1, (b), GDPR.

b. Reviews

If you are leaving a review about a delivered household service, HELPLING will process the data provided by you for the purpose of displaying the review on our platform. Legal basis of this data processing is Article 6, paragraph 1, (b), GDPR.

c. Advertising consent for your user profile data

If you have consented to receiving promotional offers from us, we process and use your user profile data, booking data and additional data as well as your access time of your user profile to understand your usage habits better and to contact you with informative information on additional services that might be of interest for you. You can withdraw your consent for promotional purposes (e.g. Newsletter) at any time using the unsubscribe link available in every email as well or by sending an email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) Legal basis for this processing is Article 6, paragraph 1, (a), GDPR.

d. Update/Deletion of profile data

You are able to update your additional information and user data at any time in your user profile. If you want to delete your user profile HELPLING will block your data first and then delete afterwards.

3\. Special notes for cleaners and service providers

a. Registration and mediation

If you are registering as a cleaner on our platform HELPLING processes the following data for the purpose of being able to initiate and potentially close a contract with you regarding the arrangement of household services:

First name, last name, email address, street, house number, postcode, city, nationality, date of birth and telephone number (hereinafter combined referred to as “partner profile data”), information on whether you are allowed to work as self-employed , your previous cleaning experience, information on your access to means of transportation, your bank details, your language skills, information on the work area and the potential timeframe of your availability and your access to different means of communication (mobile phone, smartphone, internet access) (hereinafter combined referred to as “data cleaner”). In addition, you are able to provide / upload a picture of yourself as well as short description of yourself.

HELPLING stores your profile data and such information that is created as part of the accounting of arranged cleans in a profile for cleaners, which can be accessed by you. Some of the stored profile data will also be published on our website, especially your first name, picture and short description.

Cleaner profile data is used by HELPLING for the purpose of fulfilment, completion and accounting of booked cleans/services as well as contracts including additional related actions such as invoices, credit, claims, cancellations etc and is stored in the respective profile.

In addition, HELPLING uses cleaner profile data, especially your telephone number, to send out automatic messages to notify and remind of upcoming cleaning events.

Legal basis for this data processing is Article 6, paragraph 1, (b), GDPR.

b. Reviews

If a user leaves a review on our platform, HELPLING will process this data for the purpose of displaying the review on the platform. Reviews are an integral part of our platform to ensure the utmost transparency for users.

Legal basis for this data processing is Article 6, paragraph 1, (b), GDPR.

c. Deletion

In case you want to delete your Helpling profile, HELPLING will block your data first and then delete afterwards.

4\. Communication via our platform

We offer users and service providers the opportunity to communicate directly with each other via our platform. In order to be able to offer this service, it is necessary for us to store and process the communication contents. The service is part of the platform provided by us. The legal basis for this type of data processing is Article 6, paragraph 1, (b), GDPR. The use of this service is voluntary.

We treat this communication data confidentially. As a matter of principle, we do not take note of the contents. However, we reserve the right to manually check the communication content in individual cases if there are grounds to suspect that the service is being used to circumvent our platform or otherwise to engage in fraudulent conduct or that the use otherwise violates our Terms of Use or legal regulations. In this case, the processing of data by us is based on the legal basis of Article 6, paragraph 1, (f), GDPR and serves our legitimate interest in preventing misuse of our platform.

The communication contents are stored until the profile used on the platform is deleted.

5\. Processing Server Log Files

When using our website for informational purposes only, general data is initially stored automatically (i.e. not via registration) and transmitted to our server by your browser. By default, these include: the browser type/version, the operating system used, the page accessed, the page previously visited (referrer URL), the IP address, the date and time of the server request and the HTTP status code.

The processing is carried out for the purposes of our legitimate interests, the legal basis of which is Article 6, paragraph 1, (f), GDPR. This processing is used for technical administration and website security. Stored data will be deleted after seven days unless there are concrete reference points for potential unlawful use that require further examination and processing of this data.

6\. Blog

We offer a blog on our website in which we publish articles on various topics. Our blog includes a commenting functionality, which requires the entry of personal data if used. In case you are leaving a comment, this comment will be published with the user name you provided in the respective article. We thus recommend that you use a pseudonym instead of using your full name as your user name. To use the commenting function, it is mandatory to provide an email address and user name. All other data provided is made on a voluntary basis. Legal basis for this data processing is Article 6, paragraph 1, (b), GDPR.

When you are posting a comment we also store your IP address in addition to the aforementioned data. Legal basis for the storage of your email address and your IP address is Article 6, paragraph 1, (f), GDPR. We will only use your email address in case a third party notifies us about unlawful content and we will need to examine the incident. Your IP address is stored for the purpose of being able to defend ourselves against third party rights in case you posted unlawful content. Your email address is stored for as long your comment is publicly visible. Your IP address is deleted one week after your comment was published.

In general, we do not check posted comments before publishing. We do nevertheless reserve the right to delete your comments, if third parties claim that the comment is unlawful. You are able to object to the storage of the mentioned data at any time. In this case we need to delete your comment from our website.

7\. Job Applications

You can apply for an open position with us through our website. To this end, we collect personal contact data from you, which specifically includes your name, your CV, your cover letter and other content provided by you.

We use Personio GmbH from Munich, Germany as a software partner for application processing. They are strictly bound by our instructions based on statutory requirements for order data processing. Please also refer to additional data protection guidelines on the career section of our website.

Your personal application data will only be collected, stored, processed and used for purposes in connection with your interest in current or future employment with us and the actual processing of your application. Your online application will only be processed and handled by the relevant contact people in our company. All employees entrusted with data processing are obliged to maintain the confidentiality of your data.

If we store your application data for longer than six months and you have specifically agreed to this, we inform you that this consent can be withdrawn at any time based on Article 7, paragraph 3 GDPR. Withdrawal of the consent does not affect the legality of processing done until you declared your withdrawal.

In case we are unable to offer you any employment, we will keep the data provided by you for up to six months after the end of the application process for the purpose of answering questions in relation to your application and rejection. This is not applicable in case there are statutory obligations preventing a deletion, the continued storage is needed for the purpose of evidence documentation or you have specifically agreed to a longer period of storage.

8\. Messages to us

If you send us a message via one of mentioned means of communication, we will process the data provided by you only to handle your request. Legal basis for this data processing is Article 6, paragraph 1, (b), GDPR.

9\. Newsletter

a. Subscription and Cancellation

We offer the option to subscribe to our newsletter on our website. To receive our newsletter, you will need a valid email address and your name. To verify your email address, you will first receive a subscription email, which you need to confirm (double opt-in).

We are sending you our newsletter on the basis of your confirmation (Article 6, paragraph 1, (a), GDPR). You can stop receiving our newsletter at any time in the future. You can do so easily by using the unsubscribe link available in any email or contact us via one of our mentioned communications channels (e.g. at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)).

By registering for the newsletter, we will save your IP address and date and time of registration. The processing of this data is necessary to provide evidence of the registration process in accordance with statutory requirements.

b. Analysis

We analyse the reading habits and open rates of our newsletters. We therefore collect and process pseudonymized usage data, which we will not compare to your email or IP address. Legal basis for the analysis of our newsletters is Article 6, paragraph 1, (f), GDPR and serves our legitimate interest to optimize our newsletters. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us via one of the mentioned contact channels.

c. Newsletter service

We use the newsletter service MailChimp, a service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC 675 Ponce de, Leon Avenue NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308, USA, hereinafter referred to as “Mailchimp”. Mailchimp works with us as a data processor, is strictly bound by instructions and contractually committed to ensure adequate technical and organizational data protection measures. MailChimp is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation: See more [here.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TO6hAAG&status=Active)

10\. Cookies

We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small text files that are stored by your browser when you visit a website. This identifies the browser used and can be recognized by our web server. Insofar as this use of cookies results in the processing of personal data, the legal basis for this is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Point (f), GDPR. This manner of processing serves our legitimate interest in making our website more user-friendly, effective and secure.

Most of the cookies we use are known as “session cookies”. They are deleted after the end of your visit. Other cookies (“persistent cookies”) are automatically deleted after a specified period, which may vary depending on the cookie. You can delete cookies at any time in the security settings of your browser. You can object to the use of cookies in principle or in specific cases through your browser settings.

11\. Analysis of our website

a. Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, hereinafter referred to as “Google“. Google Analytics employs cookies. The information generated by these cookies about your usage of our website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate user usage of our site, to compile reports on website activity for us, and to provide other services related to website and internet usage. It is possible to create pseudonymous user profiles using this information.

We use Google Analytics only with an active IP anonymization feature on our website. In doing so, Google abbreviates and thereby anonymizes your IP address within member states of the European Union or signatory states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is transferred to a Google server in the USA and is abbreviated there. The IP address transmitted by your browser within the context of Google Analytics will not be combined with any other data held by Google.

The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR and serves our legitimate interest to ensure a needs and demand-driven layout of our website and services.

You may prevent or stop the data processing at any time. To do this you can download and install a browser plugin that blocks tracking services or can adjust the settings on your browser software accordingly to prevent cookies from being installed.

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation. See more [here.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)

b. Optimizely

Our website uses Optimizely, a web analytics service provided by Optimizely, Inc., 631 Howard Street, Suite 100, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA, hereinafter referred to as "Optimizely". Optimizely helps us to improve our website to meet your demands better. This tool uses cookies. The information about your use of this website collected by the cookies, will be transmitted to and stored by Optimizely, usually on servers in the United States. We use Optimizely only with an active IP anonymization feature on our website, meaning Optimizely will truncate your IP address for member states of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address will be sent to and truncated by Optimizely servers in the USA.

On our behalf Optimizely will use this information for evaluating your use of the website and compiling reports on your website activity for website operators. Your IP address will not be associated with any other data held by Optimizely.

The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR and serves our legitimate interest to ensure a preferably needs and demand-driven layout of our website and services.

You may prevent or stop the data processing at any time. To do this you can download and install a browser plugin that blocks tracking services or can adjust the settings on your browser software accordingly to prevent cookies from being installed. Furthermore, you can prevent Optimizely from tracking your activity (collecting and using data, incl. cookies and your IP address) by following the instructions provided on [this website.](http://www.optimizely.com/opt_out)

Optimizely is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation. See more [here.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TNkWAAW&status=Active)

c. Hotjar

Our website uses a plugin provided by Hotjar Ltd., St Julian’s Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julian’s STJ 1000, Malta, hereinafter referred to as “Hotjar”, which enables us to measure and evaluate usage behavior on our website using so called “Heatmaps”. Furthermore, it is possible to gather feedback directly from users of the website. By using this tool, we receive valuable information to create a better performing and more user-friendly website.

Using Hotjar allows us to track clicks, mouse movements, scrolling height, screen size of your device, device type and browser information. In addition, we receive information about geographical location (country only) and your preferred language for viewing our website. In case your personal data or that of a third party is displayed on the website, this will be automatically hidden by Hotjar and cannot be retraced by the tool at any point in time.

The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR and serves our legitimate interest to ensure a preferably needs and demand-driven layout of our website and services.

You may prevent or stop the data processing at any time. To do this you can download and install a browser plugin that blocks tracking services or can adjust the settings on your browser software accordingly to prevent cookies from being installed. You can also prevent Hotjar from collecting data if you visit [this website](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out) and click on “Disable Hotjar”. You can find further information on Hotjar’s data protection [here.](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy)

d. New Relic

Our website uses New Relic, a web analytics service provided by New Relic Inc., 188 Spear Street, Suite 1200 San Francisco, CA 94105, USA, hereinafter referred to as "New Relic". New Relic is a tool that collects user data on a website to analyse and monitor its performance, e.g. to improve load times of a website.

The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR and serves our legitimate interest to ensure technical optimization of our website.

You may prevent or stop the data processing at any time. To do this you can download and install a browser plugin that blocks advertising content and tracking services, or you can adjust the settings on your browser software accordingly to prevent cookies from being installed. More information on data protection and the cookies used can be found [here.](http://newrelic.com/privacy)

New Relic is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation: [here.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TNPiAAO&status=Active)

e. Matomo

Our website uses the web analytics service Matomo (formerly known as Piwik). Matomo is an open-source software for website optimization that uses cookies for the statistical evaluation of visitor access. Your IP-address will be made anonymous immediately after the processing and before its storage. There is thus no additional processing of personal data when using Matomo. The information generated by the cookies about your use of this online service are not used for analysis specific to the individual or profile creation and are not passed on to third parties.

This data processing serves our legitimate interest to provide a needs and demand-driven website and service. The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

You may prevent or stop the data processing at any time. To do this you can download and install a browser plugin that blocks tracking services or can adjust the settings on your browser software accordingly to prevent cookies from being installed.

12\. Tracking & Retargeting

a. Facebook (visitor action pixels)

Our website uses “visitor action pixels” from Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland, hereinafter referred to as “Facebook”.

The visitor action pixel allows user behavior to be tracked after they have been redirected to the provider’s website by clicking on a Facebook ad. This enables us to measure the effectiveness of Facebook ads for statistical and market research purposes. The data collected in this way is anonymous to us, i.e. we do not see the personal data of individual users. However, this data is stored and processed by Facebook, which is why we are informing you, based on our knowledge of the situation. Facebook may link this information to your Facebook account and also use it for its own promotional purposes, in accordance with Facebook’s Data Usage Policy. See more [here.](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)

The visitor action pixel is triggered by Facebook when visiting our website and may store a cookie on your device. If you log into Facebook after this or visit our website when logged into Facebook, the visit to our website will be linked to your account. The personal data collected still remains anonymous to us and does not allow us to make any assumptions about the identity of users. This data is nevertheless stored and processed by Facebook, so that it might be possible to link this to respective user accounts and can be used for market research or other promotional purposes by Facebook.

The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR and serves our legitimate commercial interests.

You can object to the collection of your data by Facebook pixel, or to the use of your data for the purpose of displaying Facebook ads [here](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads)

Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation. See more [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active).

b. Facebook Custom Audiences

Our website uses "Custom Audiences", provided by Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland, hereinafter referred to as "Facebook". A remarketing pixel is integrated on our website through which Facebook can capture users of our website and use their data as basis for ads (Facebook Ads). Through this pixel, general information on your browser session will be sent to Facebook as well as an irreversible checksum (hash value) – not specific to the individual - which is generated from your Facebook ID. Further information on Facebook’s use of data and your rights and settings options to protect your personal data are available [here](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation).

The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR and serves our legitimate commercial interests.

Should you wish to disable Facebook Website Custom Audiences in the future you can opt out [here](https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences).

Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation. See more [here.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active)

c. Google Marketing Services

Our website uses marketing and remarketing services of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, hereinafter referred to as “Google”. These services allow us to display advertisements in a more targeted manner in order to present advertisements of interest to users. Through remarketing, ads and products are displayed to users relating to an interest established by activity on other websites within the Google network. For these purposes, a code is used by Google when our website is accessed and what are referred to as (re)marketing tags are incorporated into the website. With their help, an individual cookie, i.e. a small file, is stored on the user’s device (comparable technologies may also be used instead of cookies). Cookies can be set by various domains, including google.com, doubleclick.net, invitemedia.com, admeld.com, googlesyndication.com or googleadservices.com. This file records which apps users have visited, which content they are interested in and which offers have been used. In addition, technical information about the browser and operating system, referring websites, the length of the visit as well as any additional data about the use of the online products and services are stored. The IP address of users is also recorded, although we would like inform you that within the framework of Google Analytics, IP addresses within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area are truncated.

All user data will only be processed as pseudonymous data. Google does not store any names or email addresses. All displayed ads are therefore not displayed specifically for a person, but for the owner of the cookie. This information is collected by Google and transmitted to and stored by servers in the USA.

One of the Google marketing services we use is the online advertising program Google AdWords. In the case of Google AdWords, each AdWords customer receives a different conversion cookie. Cookies can therefore not be tracked through the websites of AdWords customers. The information collected by the cookie is used to generate conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have opted for conversion tracking. AdWords customers see the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a page with a conversion tracking tag. However, they will not receive any information that personally identifies users.

We may include third-party advertisements based on the Google Marketing Service called DoubleClick. DoubleClick uses cookies to enable Google and its partner websites to place ads based on users’ visits to this website or other websites on the Internet.

More information about Google’s use of data regarding sites that use Google Services can be found [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners). General information on the use of data for marketing purposes is available [here](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads).

The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR and serves our legitimate commercial interests.

If you wish to object to interest-based advertising by Google marketing services, you can do so using the settings and opt-out options provided by Google [here](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences).

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees its compliance with European data protection legislation. See more [here.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)

d. Microsoft Bing Ads

We use the conversion and tracking tool Bing Ads from Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, hereinafter referred to as “Microsoft” on our website. Microsoft stores a cookie on the user’s computer to enable an analysis of the use of our online services. The prerequisite for this is that the user has accessed our website through an ad from Microsoft Bing Ads. This enables Microsoft and us to know that someone has clicked on an ad, has been redirected to our online services and has reached a predetermined target page. We only see the total number of users who clicked on a Bing ad and were then forwarded to the target page (conversions). No IP addresses are stored. No other personal information about the identity of the user will be disclosed.

The legal basis for the use of this service is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR and serves our legitimate commercial interests.

If you do not wish to participate in the Bing Ads tracking process, you can communicate your objection to Microsoft [here](https://account.microsoft.com/privacy/ad-settings). Users can find further information on data protection and the cookies used at Microsoft Bing ads in Microsoft’s data protection declaration [here.](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-GB/privacystatement)

Microsoft is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation: [here.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000KzNaAAK&status=Active)

13\. Social Plug-Ins

We use Social Plugins on our website, hereinafter referred to as “Plugins“. These plugins allow you to share content from our website on different social networks. To integrate a plugin on our website the plugin’s program-code is directly transferred from the servers of the respective provider of the plugin when accessing our website. It is therefore a technical necessity to submit the used IP address. This submission happens independently of your interaction with the plugin (e.g. if you clicked on the Facebook “Like” button). If you are logged into your user account with the respective social network while visiting our website, or interact with the plugin, further data may be transferred. Additional information is available via the third-party companies providing these plugins (see below):

The data processing serves our legitimate commercial interest to increase the reach of our website. The legal basis for this is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

We have integrated the following third-party plugins on our website:

The plugin of the social network facebook.com , operated by Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland, hereinafter referred to as "Facebook". Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation. Learn more [here.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active) Data Protection Guidelines of Facebook as well as information on setting options to protect your privacy at Facebook are available [here](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

The plugin of the social network twitter.com, operated by Twitter International Company, One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street, Dublin 2, Ireland, hereinafter referred to as “Twitter“. Twitter certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation. Learn more [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active). The data protection policy is available [here](https://twitter.com/de/privacy). You may change your data protection settings [here](http://twitter.com/account/settings).

The plugin of the social network instagram.com, operated by Instagram LLC, 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA, hereinafter referred to as “Instagram“. Please note that processing through Instagram does not provide an adequate data protection level as per GDPR. Information on data protection at Instagram is available [here](https://help.instagram.com/196883487377501).

The plugin of the social network LinkedIn, operated by LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA, or if you are based outside the US, LinkedIn Ireland Limited, Gardner House, Wilton Plaza, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland, hereinafter referred to as “LinkedIn“. LinkedIn is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation. Learn more [here](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy). Further information on data protection at LinkedIn is available [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000L0UZAA0&status=Active).

14\. Integrated services and third-party content

We use services and content provided by third parties on our website. For this kind of integration, it is technically necessary to process your IP address so that the content can be sent to your browser. Your IP address will therefore be transmitted to the respective third-party provider.

In each case, this data processing is carried out to safeguard our legitimate interests in the optimization and the commercial operations of our website.

The Java programming language is regularly used to integrate content. Therefore, you can object to data processing by deactivating Java operations in your browser. Please note that this might restrict the usage of our website.

For displaying maps we use “Google Maps”, which is provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, hereinafter referred to as “Google“. Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement and thus guarantees compliance with European data protection legislation. Learn more [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active).

For displaying videos we are using “YouTube”, provided by YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA, hereinafter referred to as “YouTube“. YouTube is a daughter company of Google and thus included in their Privacy Shield certification.

We also use the content delivery network Cloudflare, provided by Cloudflare, Inc., 01 Townsend St San Francisco, CA 94107, USA, hereinafter referred to as “Cloudflare“, to cache the website in order to maintain our online offering in case of overloading of our servers. Please note that processing through Cloudflare does not provide an adequate data protection level as per GDPR.

15\. Withdrawal of consent

You are entitled to withdraw your consent to data processing in accordance with Article 7, Paragraph 3 GDPR. Withdrawal of consent does not affect the legality of processing done before you declared your withdrawal.

16\. Your rights

As the person concerned, you are entitled to exercise your rights against us. In particular, you have the following rights:

  * In accordance with Article 15 GDPR, you have the right to request information as to whether or not, and to what extent, we process personal data about you.

  * You have the right to have us correct your data in accordance with Article 16 GDPR.

  * You have the right to have us delete your personal data in accordance with Article 17 GDPR.

  * You have the right to have the processing of your personal data restricted in accordance with Article 18 GDPR.

  * You have the right, in accordance with Article 20 GDPR, to receive the personal data concerning you that you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to transmit this data to another controller.

17\. Right to object

In accordance with Article 21 GDPR, you have the right to object to any processing operations executed that use Article 6, Paragraph 1, Points (e) and (f) GDPR as their legal basis. If personal data was used by us for the purpose of direct mail you may also object to this processing in accordance with Article 3, Paragraph 2 and 3 GDPR.

18\. Complaints to Government Authorities

If you believe that the processing of your personal data constitutes an infringement of the provisions of the GDPR, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in accordance with Article 77 GDPR.
